<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>kmplot.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKmPlotxx</name>
  <summary>Mathematical Function Plotter</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Traçador de funcions matemàtiques</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Traçador de funcions matemàtiques</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Matemaattisten funktioiden piirturi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Traceur de fonction mathématique</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Wiskundige functieplotter</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Desenho de funções matemáticas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Графобудівник математичних функцій</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxMathematical Function Plotterxx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>KmPlot is a program to plot graphs of functions, their integrals or derivatives. The graphs can be colorized and the view is highly configurable, is scalable, and can be zoomed. The program features a powerful mathematical parser, different plot types (cartesian, parametric, polar, implicit, differential), and provides simple mathematical tools like for finding maximum/minimum of a function. Parametrized functions can be visualized by adjusting the variable parameter via a slider. Plots can be exported as bitmap format pictures (BMP, PNG) and can be printed.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El KmPlot és un programa per traçar gràfics o funcions, les seves integrals o derivatives. Els gràfics es poden acolorir i la visualització és molt configurable, es pot escalar, i s'hi pot fer zoom. El programa disposa d'un potent analitzador matemàtic, diferents tipus de gràfics (cartesians, paramètrics, polars, implícits, diferencials), i proporciona eines matemàtiques senzilles com la cerca del màxim i mínim d'una funció. Les funcions paramètriques es poden visualitzar ajustant el paràmetre variable des d'un control lliscant. Els gràfics es poden exportar a imatges en format de mapa de bits (BMP, PNG) i es poden imprimir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">El KmPlot és un programa per traçar gràfics o funcions, les seues integrals o derivatives. Els gràfics es poden acolorir i la visualització és molt configurable, es pot escalar, i s'hi pot fer zoom. El programa disposa d'un potent analitzador matemàtic, diferents tipus de gràfics (cartesians, paramètrics, polars, implícits, diferencials), i proporciona eines matemàtiques senzilles com la cerca del màxim i mínim d'una funció. Les funcions paramètriques es poden visualitzar ajustant el paràmetre variable des d'un control lliscant. Els gràfics es poden exportar a imatges en format de mapa de bits (BMP, PNG) i es poden imprimir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">KmPlot on ohjelma, jolla voi piirtää funktioiden kuvaajia sekä niiden integraalien ja derivaattojen kuvaajia. Kullekin kuvaajalle voi valita värin, ja näkymän voi säätää sopivaksi: sitä voi esimerkiksi skaalata ja zoomata. Ohjelmassa on tehokas matematiikkajäsennin, useita kuvaajatyyppejä (karteesinen, parametrinen, polaarinen, implisiittinen, differentiaalinen) ja työkalut funktion maksimin ja minimin etsimiseksi. Parametrifunktiot voi visualisoida säätämällä parametrin arvoa liukusäätimellä. Kuvaajat voi tulostaa ja viedä bittikarttakuviksi (BMP, PNG).</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">KmPlot est un programmer pour tracer des courbes de fonctions, de leurs intégrales ou de leurs dérivées. Les courbes peuvent être colorées et l'affichage est complètement configurable, avec prise en charge du zoom. Le programme fournit un analyseur de syntaxe mathématique puissant, différents types de tracés (cartésiens, paramétriques, polaires, implicites, différentiels), et fournit des outils mathématiques simples permettant par exemple de trouver le maximum ou le minimum d'une fonction. Les fonctions paramétriques peuvent être affichées en ajustant les paramètres grâce à un curseur. Les tracés peuvent être exportés dans des formats d'images matricielles (BMP, PNG) et peuvent être imprimés.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">KmPlot is een programma voor het plotten van grafieken van functies, hun integralen en afgeleiden. De grafieken kunnen worden gekleurd, en het beeld is in hoge mate te configureren, schaalbaar en er kan in worden gezoomd. Het programma kan heel goed wiskundige formules lezen, kent diverse plottypes (cartesisch, parametrisch, polair, impliciet, differentieel), en heeft enkele eenvoudige wiskundige hulpmiddelen aan boord voor het vinden van de uiterste waarden (minimum en maximum) van een functie. Parametrische functies kunnen worden bekeken door de variabele parameter te wijzigen met behulp van een schuifbalk. Plots kunnen worden geëxporteerd als bitmaps (BMP, PNG), en kunnen worden afgedrukt.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">KmPlot é um programa para desenhar gráficos de funções, suas integrais e derivadas. Os gráficos podem ser coloridos e a área de visualização é bastante configurável, escalável e pode ser ampliada/reduzida. O programa possui um processador matemático poderoso, diferentes tipos de gráficos (cartesianos, paramétricos, polares, implícitos, diferenciais) e oferece ferramentas matemáticas simples, como a descoberta dos valores máximos/mínimos de uma função. As funções parametrizadas podem ser visualizadas se ajustar o parâmetro variável com uma barra deslizante. Os gráficos podem ser impressos e também exportados como imagens (BMP, PNG).</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KmPlot — програма для малювання графіків функцій, їхніх первісних або похідних. Передбачено можливість розфарбовування ліній графіків та гнучкі налаштування панелі перегляду з можливістю зміни масштабу та пересування області перегляду на площині. У програмі ви зможете скористатися потужним засобом обробки формул, накреслити графіки декількох типів (у декартовій та полярній системах координат, графіки функцій заданих параметрично, неявно, графіки похідних) та скористатися простими математичними інструментами, зокрема інструментом пошуку мінімумів та максимумів функції. Передбачено можливість роботи з параметризованими функціями, зміну параметра у яких можна здійснювати за допомогою повзунка змінної. Зображення графіків можна експортувати до файлів растрових зображень (BMP, PNG) та друкувати.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKmPlot is a program to plot graphs of functions, their integrals or derivatives. The graphs can be colorized and the view is highly configurable, is scalable, and can be zoomed. The program features a powerful mathematical parser, different plot types (cartesian, parametric, polar, implicit, differential), and provides simple mathematical tools like for finding maximum/minimum of a function. Parametrized functions can be visualized by adjusting the variable parameter via a slider. Plots can be exported as bitmap format pictures (BMP, PNG) and can be printed.xx</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/kmplot/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kmplot</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/kmplot/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://edu.kde.org/images/screenshots/kmplot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kmplot</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
